Finding Aid for the James B. Coover Collection of Bibliographic Catalogs, 1690-1994
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
- Bibliographic catalogs, 1690-1994, I.; Items 1-155
  - Sotheby Parke Bernet & Co.. Catalogue of the highly important Toulouse-Philidor collection: of manuscript and printed music and other valuable manuscripts and printed books ... which will be sold by auction by Sotheby Parke Bernet & Co. ... Day of sale, Monday 26th June, 1978, 1978-06-26, 87 pag
    Bound with: Letter from Albi Rosenthal to James Coover, 1978-10-12 -- Livres de musique du Comte de Toulouse: Cantates, motets, operas, ballets, partitions gravees ou imprimees, materiel instrumental et vocal; Manuscrits de Philidor ... Laurin, Guilloux, Buffetaud, Tailleur, 1978-11-30 -- The catalogue of manuscripts in the library of St. Michael's College Tenbury [Selections], compiled by Edmund H. Fellowes, Editions de l'oiseau lyre, Paris, 1934 -- La collection Philidor [in Dernier musiciana], J. B. Weckerlin -- La collection Philidor au Conservatoire de Musique de Paris, 1874 -- The Philidor manuscripts, Paris, Versailles, Tenbury, Fellowes, Music and Letters, 1931 -- A propos de la Collection Philidor, from Un musicien en vacances, Eugene Gautier, 1873 -- The Toulouse-Philidor Collection, College Music Symposium, Charles Michael Carroll, 1979.
  - Christie, Manson & Woods International Inc.. Richard Wagner collection formed by The Honourable Mrs. Mary Burrell: the property of the Curtis Institute of Music, Philadelphia: exhibition ... which will be sold on Friday, October 27, 1978 …, 1978-10-27, 172 pages (Box 5, Item 130)
    New York (N.Y.): Christie, Manson & Woods International Inc.
    132 lots. Annotated with estimates, buyers' names and prices in MS.
    Named collector(s): Wagner, Richard; Burrell, Mary; Curtis Institute of Music
  - Sotheby Parke Bernet Inc.. Printed books & autograph letters … Musical autograph letters ... from the collections of the late Niels Hansen Christensen, Count Michael Andrassy, The Franklin Institute, Philadelphia, and other private collections, 1978-11-28, 104 unnumbered pages (Box 5, Item 131)
    Additional title: Printed books in many fields with fine musical and literary autographs
    477 lots. Sale number 4184.
    Named collector(s): Christensen, Niels Hansen; Andrassy, Michael, Count; Franklin Institute (Philadelphia, Pa.)
  - Dawson Rare Books. Rare books on music, theatre & the dance: Catalogue No.279, 1979, 51 pages, illustrations (Box 6, Item 132)
    Additional title: Catalogue no. 279
    London (England): Dawson Rare Books
  - Haus der Bücher (Basel, Switzerland). Bücher des 15. bis 19. Jahrhunderts aus der Bibliothek Johannes Oeschger: sowie Beiträge aus weiteren Privatsammlungen: Inkunabeln und Drucke des 16. Jahrhunderts, Alte Medizin und Naturwissenschaften, Deutsche Literatur des 17. bis 19. Jahrhunderts, Fremdsprachige Literatur des 17. un 18. Jahrhunderts, Schöne Einbände, Geographie und Geschichte, Helvetica sowie eine grössere Musikbibliothek, dabei 2 Mozart-Autographen, ein frühes Pastell-Porträt Mozarts und eine Sammlung von Mozart-Sekundärliteratur, 1979-06-18, 196 pages, 13 plates (Box 6, Item 133)
    Additional title: Auktion 56
    1044 lots. With full-color full-page early portrait of Mozart.
    Named collector(s): Oeschger, Johannes
  - Laurin, Guilloux, Buffetaud, Tailleur (Firm). Manuscrits musicaux, lettres autographes, Epreuves corrigees, Partitions dedicacees. Portraits de musiciens, 1979-12-14, 76 unnumbered pages, plates on almost every page, some in color (Box 6, Item 134)
    Additional title: Vente… 14 dëcembre 1979 … Manuscrits musicaux, lettres autographes … Partitions …
    165 lots. Chiefly French composers.
  - Hauswedell & Nolte. Wertvolle Bücher und Autographen, Musik: aus zwei amerikanischen Privatbibliotheken, 1980-12-09, 343 pages (Box 6, Item 135)
    Additional title: Auktion 236
    Hamburg (Germany): Hauswedell & Nolte
    2561 lots. Catalog of an auction, December 9-10, 1980.
  - A. Gerits (Hilversum, Netherlands). Rare music collection, 1981?, 26 pages (Box 6, Item 136)
    Hilversum (Netherlands): A. Gerits
  - Gary L. Steigerwald (Firm). Books about books and related subjects: Catalogue four, 1982, 56 pages (Box 6, Item 137)
    Additional title: Catalogue four
    Bloomington (Ind.): Gary L. Steigerwald, bookseller
    813 lots.
  - Humanities Research Center and the General Libraries, University of Texas at Austin. Library Chronicle of the University of Texas at Austin, New series, number 25/26, 1984, 149 pages (Box 6, Item 138)
    Austin (Tex.): University of Texas at Austin
    Named collector(s): Bachmann, Edwin; Cortot, Alfred
    Contains: Newly acquired French music manuscripts at HRC -- The Edwin Bachmann Collection: perspectives on early editions of solo and chamber music with keyboard / Ronald C. Clinton -- Sacred vocal music from the collection of Alfred Cortot / Dell Hollingsworth -- From a vison of death to the genesis of "Pénélope": the Gabriel Fauré manuscript collection / Robert Orledge -- A gradual diminuendo: Debussy and the "Trois ballades de François Villon" / Susan Youens -- "Façade" and the music of Sir William Walton / Stewart R. Craggs -- "Townsman" and music: Ezra Pound's letters to Ronald Duncan / Archie Henderson -- From Bird to Schoenberg: The Ross Russell collection / Richard Lawn.
  - Ken Leach (Firm). First century of American hymnals, 1984-11-16, 19 pages (Box 6, Item 139)
    Additional title: American hymnal collection
    Brattleborough (Vt.): Ken Leach Rare Books
    Chronologically arranged list; dated based on accompanying letter. Second, seemingly identical copy bound in.
  - J & J Lubrano (Firm). Richard Wagner, 1813-1883: the John Chancellor collection of books relating to Richard Wagner, 1985, 27 pages (Box 6, Item 140)
    Additional title: John Chancellor collection of books relating to Richard Wagner
    South Lee (Mass.): J. & J. Lubrano
    List of sales prices included.
    Named collector(s): Wagner, Richard
  - Bloomsbury Book Auctions (Firm). Catalogue of printed books, music and manuscripts, including the property of F. W. Sternfeld and the property of the Brooklyn Public Library, New York., 1986-12-18, 15 pages (Box 6, Item 141)
    Additional title: Sale 68
    London (England): Bloomsbury Book Auctions
    94 lots. Sternfeld's, lots 1-93. "… including … Autograph full score of an unpublished Intermezzo of Hindemith; an interesting series of letters of Milhaud; and an extensive collection of books on the history of music"--Cover.
    Named collector(s): Sternfeld, Frederick W.
  - H. P. Kraus (Firm). Bibliography: Part I. Antiquarian bibliography before 1850; Part II. Catalogies: provate libraries, auctions, booksellers; Part III. General bibliography, 1987, 58 pages (Box 6, Item 142)
    Additional title: Catalogue 175
    New York (N.Y.): H. P. Kraus
    983 lots.
  - Swann Galleries. Performing arts. Part I, Celebrity photographs: the remaining archive of Herbert Mitchell, "photographer of celebrities"; Part II, The Peggy Christian collection of the work of Eward Gordon Craig; Part III, Rare & antiquarian books: autographs, photographs, ephemera on all aspects of the performing arts, 1987-02-26, 1 volume (Box 6, Item 143)
    Additional title: Public auction sale number 1428, Thursday, February 26, 1987
    New York (N.Y.): Swann Galleries
    243 lots. Music & Musical Instruments, lots 119-243
    Named collector(s): Mitchell, Herbert; Christian, Peggy; Craig, Edward Gordon
  - Librairie Garnier Arnoul. Théâtre - Musique - Cinéma: Livres anciens et modernes, autographes, 1988, 165 pages (Box 6, Item 144)
    Paris (France): Librairie Garnier Arnoul
    2683 lots.
  - Galerie Gerda Bassenge. Musik, Tanz, Theater: in wertvollen Drucken und Handschriften: Lexika, Kataloge, Notendrucke, Gesangbücher, Musiktheorie und -geschichte, Biographien, Werkverzeichnisse, Graphik, Manuskripte, Autographen; mit einem Register zum Katalog der Musikbibliothek Wolffheim, 1991-05-24, 255 pages (Box 6, Item 145)
    Additional title: 57, Kunst- und Buch-Auktion Musik, Tanz, Theater
    Berlin (Germany): Galerie Gerda Bassenge
  - Phillips Son & Neale (London, England). Musical instruments, books on music, musical manuscripts, including bows of Eurpean schools, a collection of reference books at one time the property of W. E. Hill & Sons, London, a private library of scholarly music books, the property of the late A. R. de Deney, to be sold at auction Thursday 24 October 1991 …, 1991-10-24, 53 pages (Box 6, Item 146)
    Additional title: Sale no. 28,780
    London (England): Phillips, Son & Neale
    525 lots. De Deney's lots 303-427.
    Named collector(s): De Deney, A. R.
  - L. and D. McNeill (Oak Park, Ill.). Sheet music catalogue, 1992, 38 pages (Box 6, Item 147)
    Oak Park (Ill.): L. and D. McNeill
    Photocopy of typescript.
  - Phillips Son & Neale (London, England). Books on music & the theatre, scores & musical instruments to be sold by auction, 1992-10-15, 40 pages (Box 6, Item 148)
    346 lots. Sale code: 29,091.
  - Dalton, David. Primrose International Viola Archive at Brigham Young University, 1993, 52 pages (Box 6, Item 149)
    Provo (Utah): Friends of the Brigham Young University Library
    Second author: David A. Day.
    Named collector(s): Primrose, William
  - Kennys Bookshops & Art Galleries (Galway, Ireland). Singing an Irish song: Collection of Irish Music Publications, 1994, 22 pages (Box 6, Item 150)
    Additional title: Collection of Irish Music Publications
    Galway (Ireland): Kenny's Bookshops & Art Galleries
    240 lots.
  - Autographe S.A.. Autographes, lettres, documents, photos: librairie ancienne: vente sur offres, date de clôture: 28 Juin 1994, 1994-06-28, 85 pages, illustrations (Box 6, Item 151)
    Additional title: Catalogue 28
    Geneva (Switzerland): Autographe S.A.
    459 lots. Music materials, inter alia.
  - Christie, Manson & Woods International Inc.. Musical instruments: the property of a Swiss Foundation, the estates of Janos Scholz, Mark Reindorf, auction Friday, December 2, 1994 …, 1994-12-02, 70 pages (Box 6, Item 152)
    Additional title: Stradivari-8078
    166 lots. With color photographs.
    Named collector(s): Scholz, Janos; Reindorf, Mark
  - H. Baron (Firm). Manuscripts from the collection of Amalia Duodo Astori, undated, 25 unnumbered leaves (Box 6, Item 153)
    London (England): H. Baron
    209 lots, followed by facsimiles and description of 29 Rossini autograph manuscripts. Photocopy of typescript. Title from inserted slip.
    Named collector(s): Duodo, Amalia Astori
  - Unidentified. Musical library of the late Hubert Arnold (solo violinist), undated, 12 leaves (Box 6, Item 154)
    Unidentified: unpublished typescript
    Reproduced from typescript. "The library to be sold in its entirety only."
    Named collector(s): Arnold, Hubert
  - Creyghton Musicology / Musica Antiqua. Catalogue of a private collection, undated (before 1972), 97 pages (Box 6, Item 155)
    Bilthoven (Netherlands): Creyghton Musicology / Musica Antiqua, printed by N.V. Drukkerij Trio
- Binders containing title pages from sales and auction catalogs, 1717-1977, II.; Items 156-157
  Arranged by size.
  - Sales and auction catalog title pages, 1717-1977, 1 binder; Chiefly Dutch and French origins. (Box 6, Item 156)
  - Sales and auction catalog title pages, 1717-1970, 1 binder; Chiefly British origins. (Box 7, Item 157)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
Antiquarian booksellers--Catalogs; Auction houses--Catalogs; Music--Bibliography--Catalogs; Private libraries--Catalogs--Bibliography
Genres
auction catalogs; trade catalogs
Associated Material
Separated Material
Any catalogs found to be duplicates of titles held within the general collection were removed.
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
James B. Coover Papers
Collection of working papers, correspondence, and writings.